16/08/2024, 07:45 React App



# Mihail **Pesterev**

Senior Front End Developer

monya1987@gmail.com +79891311469 Telegram, WhatsApp

#### **LANGUAGES**

English (Intermediate) Russian (Native)

#### **SUMMARY**

#### Hello!

Nice to meet You and glad to see You looking into my profile. I'm a Front-End Developer with over 10+ years of experiance in web development. Looking for an opportunity to become a part of your team in any of Front-end aspects.

My expertise areas are: HTML / CSS / JS / TS / React / Redux / Next.js / Express

## **Highlights**

- Participated in the hiring process as FrontEnd interviewer.
- Mentoring \ Onboarding of newcomers.
- Had experience on architects role.
- Took an active part in the planning process, collaborating with other teams to ensure timely and efficient delivery of features.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Senior Front End Developer

2018 - 2024 (6 years)

Ecentria Solutions - https://ecentria.com/

Project: Ecommerce platform for online stores that supports 13 stores.

When i came to project the main goal was to move platforms FE to React, improving user experience and lighthouse metrics.

Part of the platform was moved to microservices architecture, also there was created "UI Design system" which was moved to separated npm package.

Personal achievements: Implement Lazy hydration, migration process from React 16 to 18, took an active part in creating \ migrating to UI Design system, several projects with improving pages performance ...

- FE: TS, React, Redux, Redux-Saga, Design system (Ariakit + vanilla-extract/css)
- SSR: react-on-rails + limenius
- Testing: Unit (Jest), End-to-end (Behat)
- Build tools: Webpack, Babel
- A/B testing: GrowthBook + GA
- Design tools: Storybook, Figma

Fullstack JS Developer (MERN)

2017 - 2018 (1 vear)

GBSFO - https://www.gbsfo.com/

Creation of a new website and admin panel for the customer.

localhost:3000/my-cv 1/2 16/08/2024, 07:45 React App



Personal achievements: Integrating GWT auth, setup UI themes with Ant Design

and Material UI.

Customers Dashboard (SPA)

• React, Redux, Material UI, MongoDB, Express, Webpack

Web Site (SSR)

• NextJS, Ant Design, MongoDB, Express, Webpack

#### Front End Developer

2013 - 2017 (3 years)

Radaris

Project radaris.com

Responsibilities: Site Support + create site aliases.

• BE: Php

• FE Build: Grunt

• FE: Bootstrap \ Foundation + JQ

## Front End Developer

2012 - 2013 (2 years)

COMODO

Dashboard for corporate users www.comodo.com

BE: Zkoss (Java framework)

Responsibilities: BE renders Vanilla js + html and most time i've just add css to rendered components.

#### Front End Developer

2010 - 2011 (1.5 years)

RingCentral

Project: www.ringcentral.com

Responsibilities: Site support + Redesign to company-developed

front-end framework.

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:**

Graduated with a Bachelor's degree in IT STEP Computer 10 Academy

localhost:3000/my-cv 2/2